# Agnese Bartolucci

agnesebartolucci505@gmail.com (+39) 3478257568 Urbino, IT Portfolio | Linkedin | Behance

Doctoral student in Visual Communication Design at Aalto University. My research interests include information design, feminism, gender studies, digital humanities, internet and social studies, and, especially, all their intersections. I believe design can play an active role in bringing changes in society and that research is the best way to achieve them. I am exploring how feminist theory can influence design and archival practices through PhD studies.

#### **Skills**

- → Academic writing and research. Conducted research for and wrote my thesis.
- → Presentation. Experienced in presenting design projects to both internal and external audiences.
- → Teamwork. Experienced in working with teams and collaborating with diverse professionals.
- → Planning. Capable of delivering projects on time through planning and organisation.
- → Problem-solving. Ability to find innovative solutions to problems with a focus on efficacy.
- → Creativity. Developed concepts from a brief through a multi-step process, including research and error-based trials.

#### **Tools**

- → Expert: Ai, Id, Ps, Lr, Figma, HTML, CSS, Word, Google Docs, Excel, Google Sheets, Keynote, PowerPoint, RAWGraphs, Gephi.
- → **Proficient**: P5.js, Tableau, OpenRefine.
- → Basic knowledge: Pr, Ae, jQuery, D3.js, QGIS.

#### Languages

- → Italian: Mothertongue
- → English: Proficient
   IELTS Academic
   Overall score: 7.5/9.0 (CEFR Level: C1)
   date 23/02/2023

#### **Personal interests**

- → Passionate reader, spanning a wide range of genres including novels and technical articles.
- → Interest in humanities with a particular love for literature and art.
- → Keen interest in the latest advancements in technology and their impact on society.

### **Current position**

SEPTEMBER 2023 - PRESENT

#### Doctoral Student, Department of Art and Media, Aalto University

I am pursuing a PhD within the Visual Communication Design Research Group, focusing on an **research project** aimed at **diversifying** perspectives in **cultural heritage digital archives** through the lens of **intersectional feminism** under the supervision of Dr Masood Masoodian.

- → OCTOBER 2023 PRESENT Code Clinic 2023 (Tutor) Teaching data visualization design and tools.
- → OCTOBER 2023 PRESENT **Visentools (Doctoral Researcher/Visual Designer)**Designing a visual language for the core product of Visentools.

#### Education

SEPTEMBER 2018 - APRIL 2022

# M.Sc. in Communication Design, Politecnico di Milano Master's Degree (110 summa cum laude/110)

I acquired a **research-based methodology** and consolidated my competencies in communication design. Particularly in **game design**, crossmedia communication, UX/UI design, and **data visualisation design**, from data collection to implementation.

- → FEBRUARY MARCH 2020 DensityDesign Open Day Presented and exhibited individual infopoetry and group projects.
- → FEBRUARY 2020 **Workshop by Edwin Jacobs and DensityDesign Lab**Created a generative and data-driven poster with the use of OPENRNDR.
- → FEBRUARY 2019 **Workshop by Gabriele Ferri and Ilaria Mariani**Designed a playable design fiction with the use of Twine.

**SEPTEMBER 2015 - JULY 2018** 

# Bachelor in Communication Design, Politecnico di Milano Bachelor's Degree (108/110)

I honed my skills in communication design, gaining expertise in **visual representation** and **graphic techniques**. I created various editorial and digital products, corporate identities, and websites.

- → FEBRUARY APRIL 2018 *Spring off the Wall* by PoliMi x Vans

  Created the concept for the event, designed the communication campaign.
- → FEBRUARY JUNE 2017 **Erasmus + at Universidad Complutense de Madrid**Deepened my editorial design and project management competencies.

## Research experience

APRIL 2021 - APRIL 2022

It's not just images. Visualizing the language of image-based sexual abuse online, advisor: Dr Gabriele Colombo

My master's degree research project focused on image-based sexual abuse (IBSA) practices and platforms involvement through the study of online vernacular language. I analysed social roots and media narration of IBSA, platform vernacular and affordances. I conducted extensive research on platforms using digital methods to examine vernacular in IBSA perpetration. I designed a website using data visualisation to present findings.

### Work experience

JUNE 2023 - OCTOBER 2023

The Visual Agency, Milano - Graphic Designer (Freelance)

I **autonomously** managed the design of different NGOs reports, involving **data visualization design** and **editorial design**.

JANUARY - APRIL 2021

#### Accurat, Milano - Data Visualization Designer (Intern)

I improved my abilities in **data visualisation design** and **team collaboration** by working on transversal projects, including dashboards for GEDI Editorial Group, data posters for Generali, and a report for the Museo Egizio of Turin.